A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, 75th Anniversary Planning Committee FA880
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, 75th Anniversary Planning Committee
1972-1976
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA880
2.51 Cubic Feet 4 document boxes and 3 half-document boxes.
7 boxes.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 600-9
Biographical / Historical
A 75th Anniversary Planning Committee was established at the University to make plans for events to mark the University's 75-year history.
The University Council sponsored an International Conference "Beyond Tomorrow - Trends and Prospects in Medical Science" for a group of invited guests and faculty. It was held on Monday March 8, 1976 in Caspary Auditorium. This was a day-long program which included lunch and a reception. The addresses by a distinguished group of speakers and panelists were published in April 1977.
The Anniversary Planning Committee arranged a Reunion Program for June 6, 7, 8, 9, 1976 to precede and include the 1976 June 9 Convocation activities. The program included a full day of colloquia, laboratory visits and discussion groups in each of ten scientific fields. A reunion plenary session was held in Caspary Auditorium on June 8, 1976 and in April 1977 the addresses were published under the title Institute to University.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
Minutes and planning correspondence Programs, publicity. Publications Tapes of Addresses.
Medical sciences; Vivisection; Genetics; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Medical care; Medical research; China; Biology -- Research; Medicine, Preventive; DNA
- 75th Anniversary Planning Committee, 1972-1976
  - Beyond Tomorrow. Correspondence, guest list, program (2 cop.) and news clippings, 1976 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reunion. Correspondence and program, 1976 June 6-9; 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Souvenir booklets (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Scientific Instruments. Catalog of instrument exhibit, 2 copies
    - An Anniversary Album. Catalog of pictures used in historical exhibition "Emendation and Correction" to Sci. Instrum., 2nd ed. (1 p.), 2 copies
  - News stories (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - MD p. 52, 62, 1976 August
    - New Yorker p. 28-29, 1976 April 5
    - Center Focus v. 1, no.40, 1976 June 7
  - Booklet Publications
    - "Beyond Tomorrow - Trends and Prospects in Medical Science" (Box 1)
    - "Institute to University" (Box 1)
  - Tapes of Addresses called: Beyond Tomorrow, Trends and Prospects in Medical Science, 1976 March 8
    Conditions Governing Access
    RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
    - Gerald Edelman, concluding portion on Reel 2 (Box 1, Reel 1)
      Access copy currently unavailable. See a RAC archivist for further instruction.
    - Clinical Investigation and Medical Education: Pressures for Choice and Change (Box 1, Reel 2)
      Scope and Contents note
      (side 2 is blank) Question period partly on Reel 3
    - Science and Technology for world problems: Opportunities and constraints. Question period continues on Reel 4 (side 2 is blank) (Box 1, Reel 3)
    - Future directions in Biomedical Research (Box 1, Reel 4)
      Patrick Haggerty
      Lewis Thomas
      Side 2 is blank
      Also "The Pursuit of Excellence"
      Frederick Seitz and David Rockefeller
  - Tapes of Addresses called: Institute to University, 1976 June 8
    - Simon Flexner and the birth of the Institute (Box 1, Reel 1)
      James Thomas Flexner
      Saul Benison
    - Oswald T. Avery and the Evolution of Modern Biomedical Science (Box 1, Reel 2)
      Maclyn McCarty
      René Dubos
    - Detlev W. Bronk and the Transition from Institute to University (Box 1, Reel 2)
      Keffer Hartline and Frank Brink
      Only in part
    - Dedication of the Detlev W. Bronk Laboratory Building (Box 1, Reel data_value_missing_fe9ff581b0c573b21bc74b935103f640)
      reel unnumbered
    - Patrick E. Haggerty (Box 1, Reel data_value_missing_be72186ebb8c4655d4da4f2d9758aee2)
  - Notes of meetings, discussions preliminary plans and ideas kept by the Ad Hoc Planning Committee for an Anniversary commemoration, 1972 December-1973 October (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Consideration of oral histories including a transcription of interview with Barney Lupinek (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notes of Continuity Committee, 1974 December-1975 May (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Note of Planning Committee, 1974 June-1975 November (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Notes of Planning Committee, 1974 September-December (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Expense Records (Box 2, Folder 6-10)
  - Records of the International Symposium held on March 8, 1976 resulting in publication "Beyond Tomorrow" Invitation lists, 1976 March 8 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lists for Trustees and Council Members to contact (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with panelists (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Clippings and press articles (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Press materials (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Biographies of speakers (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letters of appreciation (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Records, plans and lists for Reunion Program held in June 1976 before and after Convocation Ideas for Reunion, 1976 June (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Notes of Reunion Planning Committee (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Reunion invitations (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Invitation lists as compiled by various laboratories (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - Texts of addresses "Beyond Tomorrow" (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Texts of addresses "Institute to University" (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Distribution of the two published volumes (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Special edition for Carl Pforzheimer who made a contribution to finance publication of addresses (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Extra copies of "Beyond Tomorrow" program booklet, 2.5" (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Notes (Box 7, Folder 2)
    (includes correspondence, "Beyond Tomorrow" booklet, and memos).